<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adaptech Workshops on Delivering Effective Microservices</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adaptech Workshops on Delivering Effective Microservices</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike From Mike</title>
      <link>/examples/bike-from-mike/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/examples/bike-from-mike/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;BikeFromMike&amp;rdquo; is Mike&amp;rsquo;s bike rental company. He offers retailers, restaurants and other businesses a side line in bike rentals because that makes for more potential customers visiting the premises and additional revenue.
Mike provides each business with some rental bikes. Renters can see where they can pick up a bike on a nice map which shows locations and availability (while prominently featuring the products and services of participating businesses). Renters pay using the app, pick up their steed and drop it off at any other participating location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to CQRS, Event Sourcing &amp; Microservices</title>
      <link>/instructor-notes/1_introduction-to-eventsourcing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instructor-notes/1_introduction-to-eventsourcing/</guid>
      <description> Rationale Objectives Activities Evaluation Feedback </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kanban Board</title>
      <link>/examples/kanban-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/examples/kanban-board/</guid>
      <description>This can be used for explaining project phases.
Phase 1: There are three columns:
 TODO Doing Done  Tasks appear in &amp;ldquo;TODO&amp;rdquo;. When somebody starts working on the task it goes to &amp;ldquo;Doing&amp;rdquo;. When it&amp;rsquo;s done &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Done&amp;rdquo;.
Phase 2: The march of progress is not inexorable.
 It&amp;rsquo;s possible to move from &amp;ldquo;Doing&amp;rdquo; back to &amp;ldquo;TODO&amp;rdquo;. Things can become undone. (From &amp;ldquo;Done&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;TODO&amp;rdquo;.) It&amp;rsquo;s possible to delete tasks anytime, at any stage of completion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pizza Delivery</title>
      <link>/examples/pizza-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/examples/pizza-delivery/</guid>
      <description>A simple introductory example.  How we do it at &amp;ldquo;Yolanda&amp;rsquo;s Always Hot &amp;amp; Fresh?
 People pick their pizza from the online menu, special, custom, all-time favourites, drinks, etc. and phone us to order. We get their phone number and address. When a pizza is ready, it shows up on the &amp;ldquo;To Be Delivered&amp;rdquo; board. A driver makes the delivery and then marks the order as &amp;ldquo;Delivered&amp;rdquo;.
 If more than 30 minutes have passed since the order was placed, the order is put on the &amp;ldquo;Refund&amp;rdquo; screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe Review Site</title>
      <link>/examples/recipe-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/examples/recipe-reviews/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s tasty? This site is about ranking recipes - enter yours and watch the number of stars go up. Should your creation be &amp;ldquo;Culinary Star Of The Month&amp;rdquo; by gaining the most 5 star ratings you get a $500 gift certificate.
Let&amp;rsquo;s make a site where aspiring and seasoned chefs can enter their recipies. We do need their email address to tell them if they won and they want to be able to edit and delete their creations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restaurant</title>
      <link>/examples/restaurant-kitchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/examples/restaurant-kitchen/</guid>
      <description>This can be used to practice with bounded contexts and context maps. The Kitchen example can be context mapped to the columns of a Kanban board
 The kitchen point job is the toughest. You have to coordinate everybody, keep an eye on food quality, do the plating and ensure the dish completion times are the same within a table.
 # Kitchen Order Received Order Started Order Plated # Expediter Order Received Plates Allocated To Tables Order Delivered # Server Order Taken Order Placed Order Received For Delivery Order Delivered Order Paid  This is an example with three contexts and context maps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shopping Cart</title>
      <link>/examples/shopping-cart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/examples/shopping-cart/</guid>
      <description>The Shopping Cart example shows a full &amp;ldquo;real life&amp;rdquo; event storming from end to end, with multiple bounded contexts. It&amp;rsquo;s good enough to generate an API using the Adaptech platform. Shopping carts are boring, but everybody is enough of a &amp;ldquo;domain expert&amp;rdquo; to make it a suitable example for a workshop.
 &amp;ldquo;We purchase inventory. When it&amp;rsquo;s there we put it into the product catalog where people can see it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timesheets &amp; Billing</title>
      <link>/examples/timesheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/examples/timesheets/</guid>
      <description>Barney runs a consulting business. Let&amp;rsquo;s say they are lawyers or do software. The business flourishes. Clients really like the highly qualified staff and the way they come up with simple practial solutions, so the projects keep rolling in. They are usually time &amp;amp; materials: Employees or subcontractors log hours against client projects. The clients are invoiced. When working with subcontractors, Barney is billed by them and pays them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context Mapping TODO</title>
      <link>/activities/context-mapping-todo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/activities/context-mapping-todo/</guid>
      <description>Prep:  Slides with Kanban board requirements. Webeventstorming.com for same. Slides with Restaurant requirements. Webeventstorming.com for it.  Howto: Understand context mapping: (4).
 Show the Restaurant Kitchen Show the Kanban board. Discuss for 2 minutes: How would the events for the kitchen be mapped to the events on the Kanban board? Ask a table group to present what they found. Show other examples which could be mapped to a TODO list in this way, then give table groups two minutes to come up with their own examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Storming: Understanding business requirements</title>
      <link>/instructor-notes/2_event-storming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instructor-notes/2_event-storming/</guid>
      <description>Target Audience:
 Developers Leadership Project Management User Experience Designers &amp;amp; Front End Developers  Time Allotted:
30 Minutes
Rationale Event storming is a way of understanding existing and new systems at the business needs and objectives level. It gets everybody (technical and non-technical) on the same page, cutting down on meetings, coordination effort and crossed wires. It removes many frustrations and saves time by helping people to find a &amp;ldquo;shared language&amp;rdquo; in which to describe requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe Reviews - No tech jargon</title>
      <link>/activities/taking-care-of-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/activities/taking-care-of-business/</guid>
      <description>Requires an envelope with events in random order - some are business, some are technical. One per table group. Use the EMD in recipe review example. Print it with https://gogs.adaptechsolutions.ca/robert.reppel/emd-pdf.
Howto: &amp;ldquo;Take two minutes: Read the requirements. Then take a look at the events in the envelope. Try to arrange them in the right order.&amp;rdquo;
 Participants will run into difficulties putting the technical events in sequence and will start discussing implementation details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Human Eventstorming</title>
      <link>/activities/human-eventstorming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/activities/human-eventstorming/</guid>
      <description> Print this PDF: Human Eventstorming
 Ask for volunteers from the audience.
 Have each of them grab one of the printed sheets with events.
 &amp;ldquo;Now arrange yourselves in the order in which the events occur.&amp;rdquo;
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Path Less Happy</title>
      <link>/activities/the-path-less-happy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/activities/the-path-less-happy/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Understand that there is more than one path through the system and that different paths can be represented as swim lanes in an event storming diagram.
Prep:  Slide 1: Sample requirements (maybe on the wall?) and event storming. Use &amp;ldquo;Bike From Mike&amp;rdquo; example. Slide 2: Additional requirement 1 not on the happy path (delete, update, ???) Yellow postits and pens.  Howto:  &amp;ldquo;Take a look at these requirements and the event storming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Word Cloud</title>
      <link>/activities/wordcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/activities/wordcloud/</guid>
      <description>Prep: Print cards with words and phrases from three different bounded contexts, one set per table group. Put them in envelopes labeled &amp;ldquo;Word Cloud&amp;rdquo;. Tell participants to not open the envelopes until instructed to do so.
Howto &amp;ldquo;Open the &amp;lsquo;Word Cloud&amp;rdquo; envelope. Group the cards in it - which ones belong together?&amp;rdquo;
Then ask three table groups to tell a story about one of the bounded contexts without mentioning vocabulary of the other ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bounded Contexts: Establishing Service Boundaries</title>
      <link>/instructor-notes/3_strategic-ddd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instructor-notes/3_strategic-ddd/</guid>
      <description>Target Audience:
 Developers Leadership Project Management User Experience Designers &amp;amp; Front End Developers  Time Allotted:
45 min.
Rationale The trickiest part of creating effective microservices is to determine where one service ends and the next one begins. Getting this right is the secret sauce: Loose coupling and high cohesion greatly simplifies delivering and maintaining services. Bounded Contexts and the use of Ubiquitous Language to identify them are a technology agnostic and practical way of achieving this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project managing microservice projects</title>
      <link>/instructor-notes/4_project-managing-microservice-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instructor-notes/4_project-managing-microservice-projects/</guid>
      <description>Rationale Moving to CQRS and event sourced microservices drastically reduces coordination overhead and the need for regression testing.
Objectives  The pros and cons of using events instead of user stories as units of planning and tracking are understood. Participants are able to create Kanban boards for separate bounded contexts and use them for coordinating two or more teams.  Activities  Two minute war story: Turning event stormings into TODOs by rotating them 90 degrees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hands-On</title>
      <link>/instructor-notes/5_hands-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/instructor-notes/5_hands-on/</guid>
      <description> Rationale Objectives Activities Evaluation Feedback </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Sourced Project Management</title>
      <link>/activities/event-sourced-project-mgmt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/activities/event-sourced-project-mgmt/</guid>
      <description>Prep  Do (or provide result of, on webeventstorming.com) shopping cart event storming Slide: Shopping cart example bounded contexts. Slide: Blank Kanban board - TODO-Doing-Done Slide: Explain &amp;ldquo;Upstream&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Downstream&amp;rdquo; teams/bounded contexts.  Howto    Say Do     &amp;ldquo;Here are the results of the shopping cart exercise.&amp;rdquo; Show the shopping cart event storming on webeventstorming.com.   &amp;ldquo;What bounded contexts do you see?&amp;rdquo; After the audience has identified contexts, show a slide with the bounded contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivering Effective Microservices</title>
      <link>/slides/effective-microservices-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slides/effective-microservices-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Delivering Effective Microservices  Introduction To Event Sourcing &amp;amp; CQRS  Manage microservice coupling &amp;amp; cohesion Integrate legacy with events Simplify code Less meetings, less planning, better results.  Event Storming The Human Eventstorming Why?  Great for exploring large complex systems. Takes only a couple of hours. Less crossed wires. Less meetings, less &amp;ldquo;documentation&amp;rdquo;. Shared understanding, understood by all. Fun! ___  How to Event Storm https://webeventstorming.com  Note: &amp;ldquo;EMD (Event Markup Language) is a simple text notation for event storming online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>header</title>
      <link>/_header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_header/</guid>
      <description>Delivering Effective Microservices</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>